Peter Phi Tran

Full Stack Software Engineer

Dublin, OH, 43016 | tranpp87@gmail.com | 513-602-8748 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

ABOUT ME

A Full Stack Software Engineer motivated to tackle complex problems. Deliver critical thinking skills, project management and clear communication to achieve results on time. Experienced people leader and individual contributor with a unique balance and perspectives as a leader, mentor, and student.

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | MongoDB | Express | React.js | Node.js | Python Django | PostgreSQL | Project Management | CATIA V5 | Communication Client facing | Cross-functional collaboration | Mentoring | Interpersonal skills Git / GitHub

PROJECTS

Chef's Kiss, MongoDB, Express, Node.js

GitHub 🗗

- Planned and executed a personal food review app that has full CRUD functionality.
- Created RESTful backend API.
- Applied Google OAuth for user authentication.

JotDown, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

GitHub 🗷

- Designed and deployed a quick note taking app that lets you quickly jot down a note and add additional sub notes.
- Integrated RESTful conventions to build API endpoints.
- Utilized Django's built-in authentication system for login/registration.

AllTheFeels, MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js

GitHub 🔼

- Collaboratively constructed and built an app focusing on teen mental health.
- Full CRUD functionality with image upload.
- Designed and programmed pop-out navigation bar for UI/UX.
- Used IWT for authentication.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jan 2013 – Jul 2021

Honda of America Mfg.,

New Model Project Leader / Supervisor

- Implemented new equipment to reduce production downtime to nearly 0 which resulted in saving the department over \$100K a year.
- Planned and managed full product cycle with on-time launch of 2016 and 2021 Acura MDX.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams across multiple time zones to ensure correct design and manufacturability for department.
- Traveled to international and domestic suppliers to verify design, part quality and schedule to meet factory expectations and on-time delivery.
- Mentored new hires, co-ops and interns to maintain, develop and output workers of the future.

Aug 2005 - Sep 2011

Kroger Pharmacy, Pharmacy Technician

- Awarded employee of the month for providing excellence client facing customer service.
- Communicated with patients, doctor's offices, and insurance companies to prepare and fulfill prescription requests.
- Complying with rules, regulations and procedures to help maintain a clean and safe pharmacy, such as by sterilizing equipment and surfaces.

EDUCATION

Sep 2021 – Dec 2021

General Assembly, Software Engineering

- Attended and completed Software Engineering Immersive Program.
- Developed and deployed projects using Agile development workflow.
- Implemented version control using Git and GitHub.
- Gained over 500+ hours of coding experience.

Aug 2006 – Jun 2012

University of Cincinnati, Mechanical Engineering Technology ☑

- B.S. Mechanical Engineering Technology.
- ABET Accredited.